Matias Rojas

Buenos Aires, Buenos Aires Province, Argentina

matiasjulianrojas@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/mjrojas

Summary

Computer Science professional passionate about building products and teams, and solving problems. I have been working in this area for several years. Throughout my professional career I have participated in several projects for different industries where I have had the opportunity to meet people, face challenges and learn hard and soft skills that have allowed me to gain extensive experience in software development and leadership. During this time I have been exposed to many technologies, environments, processes and tools used for the development of products based on microservices in the cloud with continuous integration using agile methodologies.

Experience



X Engineering Manager

CookUnity

Jun 2023 - Nov 2023 (6 months)

M Senior Manager, Software Engineering

Medallia

Oct 2021 - Feb 2023 (1 year 5 months)

In October, 2020 I had the opportunity to build a new team for a new Signal that started to grow very fast and with high visibility at Medallia. I built a new team of 5 engineers and we double the team size one year later with engineers in different locations. We built an asynchronous architecture using Java, Spring Boot, Kafka, Redis, Rest APIs and PosgreSQL with agile methodoligies like Scrum. We are responsible for massive data ingestion for Call Centers call recordings. We process, transcribe and get valuable analytics and insights for our customers in real time.

I have the opportunity to interact not only with other engineering teams and managers but also with other teams like product, professional services, sales, VP and C level, Medallia Partners and Customers

We are scaling the architecture in order to get high performance, high availability, observabily and monitoring (grafana + prometheus) at the same time that we are adding new customer features to make the business grow and contunue being leaders in customer experience.

Manager, Software Engineering

Medallia

Feb 2019 - Oct 2021 (2 years 9 months)

I joined Medallia to lead and grow the product and engineering team of 6 members responsible for collecting unsolicited feedback from several social media networks about our customers' products and services experiences. I was responsible for people managment as well as build and scale an asyncrhorous architecture based on microservices to get these signals. The tech stack was Java, Spring Boot, Scala, Kafka, API Rest, Cassandra, PostgreSQL, React and Node.js.

Think about the last interaction you had with a company. Was it a good one? Could it have been better? Medallia was founded on a simple idea: that companies can win by putting the customer first.

Medallia gives the world's leading brands access to their customers' eyes, ears, and hearts so they can design and deliver incredible customer experiences. Our cloud-based software captures and analyzes customer feedback across multiple channels to help companies like Airbnb, Mercedes-Benz, Delta Air Lines, and Nordstrom earn the love of their customers. We're one of Sequoia Capital's largest investments, and we're growing like crazy.

https://youtu.be/Pw8HmDML_KM



Software Development Manager

Navent

Apr 2016 - Jan 2019 (2 years 10 months)

I was responsible for the Real Estate portal web across several countries of latin america like Argentina, Brazil, Mexico, Peru, Venezuela and Panama.

I had a team of 15 engineers and two tech leads. I was in charge of the people management, recruiting, product definitions, architecture design and implementation with technologies like Java, Spring Boot, MySQL, Kafka, Redis, React and Node.js.

I had to interact with other Engineering Managers and their teams to build the whole solution for the business needs.



Java Lead

Navent

Apr 2015 - Mar 2017 (2 years)

After 10 months I was able to build my own team of 4 members in charge of the product. I was in charge of the people management, recruiting, product definitions and tech debt. I was able to increase the team size up to 10 members. I defined a new architecture of the product to decouple the app from the monolith based on different microservices deployed in the cloud with technologies such as Java, Spring Boot, Rest APIs, Redis. Kafka, React, Redux and Node.js and Kubernetes. It was an exciting and successfull experience that ended out with my promotion to Development Manager.



Senior Java Developer

Navent

Jun 2014 - Mar 2015 (10 months)

I started as a Sr Software Engineer in the Real Estate portal web team of 4 members.



Tech Lead

Thomson Reuters

May 2011 - Jun 2014 (3 years 2 months)

Leading and managing Java Web and Standalone application development teams for the company's business units around the world. Participating in the technical analysis of the requirements, design and development of solutions. Responsible for the planning, estimation and execution of projects using agile development techniques, assignment and monitoring of tasks, code review, performance evaluation of the members of my team, project and team status report to the development manager, product delivery

and post production support. Direct communication with the client to understand their needs and the operation of the applications. I worked with people around the world, e.g. US, UK. Spain and India



Sr Software Developer

Thomson Reuters

Feb 2011 - Apr 2011 (3 months)

Software Developer Contractor

Apr 2010 - Feb 2011 (11 months)

I worked at the MUPIM projects that controls all the activity of the members of this entity, and Anses ARN project that manages the retirement business rules.

In both projects, I performed consulting tasks and customer features development. I had high exposure and interaction with the customer and other consultants.

Sr Software Developer and SCM

Hibu

Jun 2008 - Mar 2010 (1 year 10 months)

Software architecture definitions.

Company business core software development in Java.

Technical analysis and validation of requirements.

SCM Processes (Software Configuration Manager) definitions and planning. Release manager: Code version control (SVN, CVS), continuous integration with Jenkins and Artifactory.

Early detection of errors based on code reviews in the internal development phase and with external contractors.

Fluid communication with the leaders and contractors of all engineering projects.

Execution of stress test in the pre-production phase with Jmeter.



Ssr Software Developer

Atos

Sep 2005 - May 2008 (2 years 9 months)

June 2007 - May 2008

Software developer in the Merlin and RDV project for PSA S.A. performing the complete development of both systems in Java and Struts and Oracle Database.

January 2007 - May 2007

Software developer in Total Austral's PAM project responsible for Java development and maintenance of the web application.

September 2005 - December 2006

Software developer in the Marco Polo project for Carrefour Colombia that implements the GOLD commercial system in the stores and platforms. Migration and coexistence between the new and the old system using the SeeBeyond (JCaps) integration tool.

Education



🤍 Universidad Nacional de La Matanza

Engineer's degree, Computer Science 2002 - 2011

Skills

Webpack • SQL • Gradle • Spring Boot • Arquitectura de software • Node.js • GitLab • GitHub • CVS • Subversion